#### **CURRICULUMN VITAE**

#### **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

NAME: Bernard Awino

DOB: 23/10/1994

**GENDER: MALE** 

LANGUAGES: KISWAHILI, ENGLISH

TEL: 0706877851

EMAIL: <a href="mailto:bernardawino@gmail.com">bernardawino@gmail.com</a>

### **OBJECTIVE**

I am Software Developer/Website Designer/Database Manager with five years of programming experience in LARAVEL, DJANGO, C#, PHP, Jquery, ANGULAR, VueJs, Html5, MYSQL, JavaScript, Wordpress with a basic understanding of other programming languages. In addition to these, I am also a team leader and a committed individual who is ready to work and meet tight deadlines if need be.

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

Year	Certificate	Institution
2013-2017	Bachelor's Degree in	Laikipia University
	Computer Science	
2009-2012	Kenya Certificate of	Orero Boys Secondary
	Secondary Education	School
2001-2008	Kenya Certificate of Primary	Ongang'a Primary School
	Education	

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Duration	Duty	Company
Feb 2021 to Date	Front-end Developer	Onfonmedia Group
July 2020 to January 2021	Software Developer	Techno Brain Limited
September 2018 to June	Software Engineer/ Web	Gates Education Group
2020	Developer/ Database	
	Manager/Designer/Administrator	
Jan 2018 to August 2018	Software Engineer/Developer	Africa Cloud Space
	Database	
	manager/designer/administrator	
Nov 2016 to date	Freelance Web Developer	Papasofts Technologies
May 2016- September 2016	IT Support	Kenya Medical Supplies
		Authority (KEMSA)
May 2015- September 2015	IT Support	HomeBoyz Foundation

### ACHIEVEMENTS/ACCOMPLISHED PROJECTS

- **♣** Developed a Cloud-Based School Management System for African Cloud Space Company CloudSchool.
- **♣** Developed a blogging portal <u>themintafrica.com</u>
- ♣ Developed a Customer Relationship Management System <u>BluePrintSalesAfrica</u>
- ♣ Part of a team that developed a betting platform triple5bet.com
- Mentoring youths through a leadership program sponsored by International Christian Youthworks (ICY).

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES**

- 1. Certificate in Introductory Course to Cyber Security
- 2. Diploma in Leadership Skills
- 3. Certificate in Digital Literacy Training by the Microsoft Group
- 4. Certificate in Sales and Marketing by the HomeBoyz Foundation

# **SKILLS**

- 1. ANGULAR
- 2. C#
- 3. Jquery
- 4. Database Design(MYSQL, POSTGRESQL e.t.c)
- 5. Server Configuration and Installation
- 6. PHP/Laravel development
- 7. Sql Database Management
- 8. Web application development and Design
- 9. CSS styling
- 10. VueJs
- 11. JavaScript
- 12. DevOps
- 13. Wordpress
- 14. Database query languages (SQL, others)
- 15. Efficiency HTML 5
- 16. IT support Operating systems
- 17. PHP User experience (UX and UI) design

# **HOBBIES**

- 1. Playing/Watching Soccer
- 2. Making new friends
- 3. Coming up with new ideas
- 4. Mentoring
- 5. Learning new programming skills

# **REFEREES**

Name: Prof. Humphrey Oborah

Institution: World Talent Federation

Position: Secretary General

Tel: +254 708 805 070

NAME: Ms. Salome Ireri

Institution: Laikipia University

Email: <a href="mailto:sireri@gmail.com">sireri@gmail.com</a>

Tel: +254 723 409 982

Name: Joseph Wanjau

Institution: Africa Cloud Space

Position: Managing Director

Tel: 0720 068 297